foreign
[Music]
show today we discuss very important
issues about what's happening around the
world including some of our favorite
Nations
so let's get to and get into that
shortly but before that I need to greet
you all who all do we have we have rinal
we have arnavo r2futu Nandan Bilzerian
bruh
shubham Yash yasho radioactive cake
a Harvey on Wheels S2 h o r i four but
Jason
rajput
radioactive something dipto Aryan
and lots of other people good evening
good day to all of you shout dog
the prime mover
done Mercy
and the swastik Sudan show Rahul
siddhant Naman Chennai Yoda sudhanshu
revanth and lots of other people good
evening good at all of you I hope you're
all doing very well very well and thank
you for joining this live stream
so I I think we should begin where we
should begin we all know what is the
most important and pressing matter that
in the most uh the the biggest question
everybody has so let's get into it shall
we let us get into it
with question one this is by multiple
people Manisha Gopi Krishna ramakrishna
and lots of other people have asked
questions to this effect and the
question is
as we all notice something weird is
happening in China's government in
politics can you please explain the
matter and your assumption as to what
will happen news about XI jinping's life
imprisonment is that true you mentioned
in one of the episodes there's the
possibility of a coup in China is that
what's happening there are rumors of XI
Jin being under house arrest and being
overthrown very much in line with your
uh analysis and prediction of a coup
against the Chinese president if they
failed what do you have to say about
about these rumors yes right so yes I
have spoken about this on various
occasions about the uh potential for a
coup in China always being there and
China is a kind of is a kind of nation
the kind of society that is that has
that satisfies the preconditions for a
coup which we will get into uh in some
time so China is a nation that will
experience schools from time to time
that's the way the Chinese Communist
party is structured in the entire nation
the governance all that is structured so
I did uh mention I have spoken about
this multiple times that coups are
likely in China right and there are
certain preconditional that need to be
met first of all the the leader of China
whoever it is if that person is
perceived to have failed at something in
a major way and they lose face and they
lose the trust of the people then it's
very likely for the for a coup to happen
within the Chinese Communist Party
itself and that sort of thing so what's
happening in China well something is
something weird is happening in China so
why don't we take a look at what's
happening let's take a look at uh the
flight situation or what are the other
are the planes still flying over China
so yesterday I mean yesterday we had
less Clarity on the matter today we have
a little more clarity
I spoke about this yesterday as well and
I said that let's wait for 24 hours and
see what's happening so yesterday we saw
that over Beijing there were very few
planes flying today we see a little a
few more planes around Beijing the
airport I'm not sure if it has come back
to normalcy but what is this let's see
what this plane is
uh China Southern Airlines we don't know
where it's coming from we don't know
where it's going it's not mentioned uh
we have a Pakistani plane from Xi'an to
Beijing so there you go
and what is this one this is from
Hangzhou to Beijing so yes flights seem
to have resumed it's not as busy as you
would expect to be Beijing is one of the
uh one of the nation's most likely the
nation's busiest airport one of the
busiest airports in the whole world
actually and it's clear that even now
the situation is not quite normal
yesterday there was nothing flying over
Beijing which is incredibly unusual even
today there are very few planes aircraft
flying over Beijing and we also heard
these reports of the mass cancellations
of thousands of trains and thousands of
of flights as well so clearly something
strange is happening in China or Beijing
and so on that's what we can see right
so we can see something is wrong so what
are the potential scenarios let's talk
about the potential scenarios one
scenario is that Mr Xi Jinping we know
that Mr Xi Jinping was last seen in
public in Samarkand during the SEO
Summit which was attended by President
both in Prime Minister Modi and various
other leaders of the Nations that
comprise the SEO so Mr Xi Jinping was
last seen in public in Samarkand and he
left the summit and after that he has
not been seen typically when you are a
high profile person typically when you
are the leader of a Nation the people
the public needs to know exactly what
you're doing on a day-to-day basis if a
leader disappears for some time it makes
the nation very uneasy remember when we
had this prime minister who would not
speak when India had a prime minister
who would not speak and would not react
to anything would not appear
in public for days on end when the 2008
Mumbai attacks happened the terrorist
terrorists who came from Pakistan the
prime minister of India responded after
about a week or so yep
so when you have a leader like that it
it makes the people feel like like the
country is leaderless and rudderless and
it does not inspire a great deal of
confidence so Mr Xi Jinping has not been
seen in public for some time ever since
the SEO Summit ended which raises a
whole lot of questions because typically
he's seen on a day-to-day basis so
what's happening what are the potential
the possible scenarios of what's
Happening one scenario is maybe Mr Xi
Jinping is unwell you know he's not a
young man he is in his late 60s or
something another maybe 69 years old and
he has had a history of health issues
possibly not major issues but health
issues yes he is uh not very young he's
a kind of an overweight person so that
has its uh health risks yes and when he
was first appointed the the leader of
China which was uh in 2012 if I'm not
mistaken he disappeared for a couple of
months for some health treatment so he
has had a history of disappearing from
time to time especially in the very
beginning so one possibility is that he
has some health issue which is being
taken care of right now but that does
not explain why all the planes have been
canceled all the flights have been
canceled thousands of flights and
thousands of trains have been canceled
therefore the possibility the scenario
that Mississippi is unwell in undergoing
some treatment that scenario looks a
little unlikely yes what's the second
scenario the second scenario is that
there has indeed been a coup within the
Chinese Communist party and Mr XI jinpig
is in the under house arrest or whatever
and somebody else is is taking over and
consolidating power that is scenario
number two and that's what all the
rumors have been about all our social
media that it looks like Xi Jinping has
been put under house arrest and there's
a coup and some other General is going
to succeed him and he has taken over the
reins of the power and all that so
that's scenario number two that Mr Xi
Jinping has in indeed uh been overthrown
that that is scenario number two
that would kind of explain why so many
flights have been canceled trains have
been canceled because when a coup is
done you want to consolidate power you
don't want people to be moving around
you want everything to stay where it is
while you consolidate all the
instruments of power
so that can actually explain what's
happening but there has been a coup in
Mr Xi Jinping has been awesome and
that's why he's not visible anymore he
did not attend the various public
meetings where he was he would typically
be right so that is scenario number two
there is a third scenario my dear
friends a third scenario so now
um what's what other news has been
coming out of China Mr is not visible
but certain other things are happening
in China for instance in October there's
going to be the National Party Congress
the 20th National Party Congress of the
Chinese Communist party is going to be
in October so there's a process that
that precedes this Congress delegates
have to be elected or selected or
whatever right so the Chinese media
Outlets have reported that more than 2
200 delegates to the 20th National Party
Congress have been elected under the
leadership of Xi Jinping yeah that's
what I think shinua the shinwa news
agency said that the election of the
deputies to the 20th National Congress
has been completed it was completed just
recently right so each there are
electoral units across the country
across the across China these are all
electoral units of the Chinese Communist
party so these units held various
representative meetings or party
congresses or whatever they call it and
all these electoral units this they have
elected 2200 plus deputies who will go
and attend this 20th National Congress
of the Communist Party of China right
and this uh National Congress the
national Communist Party Congress
whatever it's called it is held once in
five years and the purpose of the
National Party Congress of the Communist
Party of China the purpose is to elect
or select or determine the leadership of
the Chinese Communist party for the next
five years essentially they are electing
a new emperor or selecting a new emperor
so every five years this National Party
Congress meets and it determines the
leadership of the CCP of the Chinese
Communist party and therefore of China
for the next five years and Mr Xi
Jinping is expected has been expected to
receive a new a third five-year term
this October which essentially paves the
way for his ascendance to the Emperor of
China or the Paramount leader of China
or Paramount leader of the party for
life
so we have three possibilities one he is
unwell that looks very unlikely second
there is a coup against him he has been
overthrown that could explain what we
are saying third
nothing is wrong
the third possibility is that there is
indeed an internal coup within the
Chinese Communist party it's a top-down
coup it is instigated by the top
leadership of China which is led by Xi
Jinping this sort of an internal coup is
called a purge
what does this mean possibly
there is a process being being
undertaken right now of purging several
high-ranking representatives of the
Chinese Communist Party those who
represent threats to Xi Jinping
and we saw it in the news you know a
couple of very ranking officials of the
Chinese Communist party like the uh
Deputy SEC whatever of defense or
whatever I don't remember the title and
the name Chinese names I find them hard
remember I apologize for that to my
Chinese friends who may be watching but
yes a couple of very high ranking
officials of the Chinese Communist Party
where uh sentenced to extremely heavy
sentences one person was sentenced to
death with a reprieve of two years
suspended a suspended death sentence
suspended by two years and that that is
a very hiring person of the Chinese
Communist party and it's possible that
this sort of process is happening at
multiple levels
at the high level of the Chinese
Communist party this is called
consolidation of power that is a kind of
coup in which the Top Dog consolidates
power by getting rid of anybody who
represents a threat to him and that
could very well explain what we are
witnessing all the trains have been
canceled Lots thousands of trains have
been canceled thousands of flights have
been canceled this in my opinion is the
most likely scenario Mr Xi Jinping has
not suffered any massive defeat he has
not lost face in any way
he has not uh let the nation down in any
way what happened in Taiwan was
something that would leave a bad taste
in the mouth for many Chinese people but
overall the situation has not changed
China has not lost any new territory
China has not suffered a military defeat
yes it was kind of a humiliation from
the U.S but that can be swallowed to
some extent right but there has been no
major failure on the on the part of Mr
Xi Jinping that would uh
would that would make the people accept
a coup or a change in leadership I am
sure they still see Xi Jinping as the
most capable leader in the Chinese
Communist party and therefore this is my
official prognosis diagnosis or
prognostication whatever you want to
call it of what's happening right now
most likely this is a consolidation of
power an internal coup an internal Purge
that is being done by Xi Jinping in
order to consolidate power further in
China and this is the preclude to him
being appointed for a third five-year
term in October which is next month so
that is what I see happening yesterday
there was no Clarity on what was going
on today we see some patterns emerging
and more news emerging out of China
about the election of all the
representatives of all the delegates to
the National Party Congress thousands of
them 2200 plus and so on all of this
seems to indicate that there is
something indeed going on the situation
in China is not normal but this most
likely is solidation of power and
internal Purge that is being done by Xi
Jinping in in in the in the Prelude to
to him being a re-elected reselected
appointed or whatever as the essentially
as the emperor for life right so that is
most likely what we are seeing the most
likely there is no coup most likely Xi
Jinping has not been most likely he has
not been overthrown it doesn't look like
that if I am wrong it's fine but this is
how I see things going I do not see him
falling from Power I see him actually
consolidating power further so most
likely that's what's happening now
obviously the next few days will tell us
exactly how things have gone if he does
reappear in October or before October
we'll know that everything is fine with
him and if something else happens then
eventually the Chinese Communist party
will have to announce uh if a leadership
change has been has been implemented but
most likely this is most likely an
internal coup within the CCP a purge of
high-ranking officials and
representatives to make way for Mr XI
jinping's reselection or appointment as
the Paramount leader of China
essentially for life so that's how I see
things going yeah
okay so deepto says yeah we know what
happened that recently reports have come
out that he may have been placed in the
rest and so on and so forth
possibilities of a coup in China what's
your take on this so I already answered
that can you predict the consequences of
the event for India and the world how
harsh will the next leader be in case a
coup succeeds
okay so in the scenario there are two
three different possibilities different
scenarios one scenario which I find
unlikely but let's take it seriously for
hypothetically yeah so let's see an
actual coup happens and let's say
someone like Xi Jinping is overthrown
and somebody else comes to power what
are the consequences of such an
eventuality for India and for the world
yeah and how harsh will this new leader
be so when a new leader when somebody
overthrows an existing leader that new
leader has to First prove himself or
herself typically it's himself in the
Chinese Communist party so that leader
will have to
demonstrate to the Chinese Communist
party and to the people of China that he
is visibly better than the predecessor
first of all he will have to make
multiple accusations of failure
on the person who he has overthrown in
order to justify himself coming to power
and overflowing the person so he will
have to say that the Xi Jinping failed
in this aspect in that aspect in Hindi
he allowed China to be humiliated in
this manner by the Americans and by the
Indians in this family or whoever else
he let the country down
humiliated the country and and so on so
forth he has to put out a list of
accusations true or false whatever that
doesn't matter a list of accusations
have to be made to justify his Ascension
to power and overthrowing the previous
leader and then he has to rapidly
demonstrate that he is better and he
will make things right
that typically is can can be a pollute
to military activity or Warfare or
something significantly strong yeah
something that uh typically someone like
would not do in a haste or in a hurry so
if somebody actually overthrows Xi
Jinping then that person will have to
take a belligerent stance against
somebody somewhere maybe against Taiwan
maybe against India maybe somewhere else
maybe Japan maybe somewhere else yeah so
maybe against the US so against the US
they cannot they don't have too many
military options open because the U.S is
massively overpowered compared to China
militarily right and even economically
the US is still very much the top dog in
the world so the Chinese don't have too
many options of uh of of taking any
really strong measures against the US
right they can ask the diplomats to go
on an all-out offensive but that's just
words verbal offensive and they can't
take too many trade measures because the
U.S can retaliate so there is not much
they can do against the US now the other
options are they have multiple
territorial disputes they will not right
now open anything with Russia because
they would like Russia to be on their
side for the time being so Russia is
again out of the question the U.S is out
of the question what does it leave it
leave us with it leaves it with uh major
Nations three uh two major Nations one
is India one is Japan and of course
these uh the Taiwan dispute which is
simmering now again when it comes to
Taiwan the Americans uh are very much
capable of protecting Taiwan and
preventing China from uh invading and
successfully invading so if the Chinese
try an invasion of Taiwan it's gonna end
up disastrously most likely for them it
will be a much worse loss of face in a
much bigger humiliation than anything
you can accuse Mr Xi Jinping of having
done so that would be a disaster for for
the Chinese so then we are left with
India and Japan so the Chinese could try
something against India and Japan and
they could try something militarily now
when it comes to Japan they have this
dispute over the senkaku islands the
Chinese call them the diyu islands right
so they could try to make a grab for
that once again the Japanese Navy is
incredibly strong the Japanese Navy is
more powerful and more lethal than the
Indian Navy please understand this their
submarines scare the heebie-jeebies out
of the Chinese the Japanese have the
best submarines in the world bar the
American submarines very good even their
even their uh obsolete submarines are
better than anything most Nations have
right the sorio class various submarines
so the Chinese would be very reluctant
to go up against Japan in any kind of
thing because that could escalate things
beyond what they would like things to go
that leaves us with India they could try
something with India we know what what
the Chinese the entire India Tibet
border boundary is undemarkated and the
Chinese always have been pushing
prodding pushing prodding nibbling away
territory trying to nibble away
territory changing the maps and putting
Chinese names on Indian places and
things like that so they could possibly
try something like like the 1961 or 1962
war with India a short sharp brief war
that will give them a very rapid and
very small military Victory which they
would hope for and then they can tell
the their and then the new leader can
tell the countrymen that you know this
is what we achieved and we have uh we we
have re-established over our uh whatever
you know our status in the world our
that we are a major Nation so they could
try something against India the one of
the likely places let's take a look at
the map right we should see the map one
of the likely places where the Chinese
could uh indulge in a misadventure
against India let's see the map and I
will show you where it is I'm sure you
all know if you've been watching this
channel one of the likely places is the
Siliguri Corridor which is approximately
50 kilometers wide right it is currently
a part of West Bengal for whatever
reason I'm not sure why but the Siliguri
corridor
and Sikkim that's one of the uh
geographically uh thinnest places in
India you know very uh very uh small
Corridor and that that can be looked
upon as one of the weak points in
India's geography and they could try and
uh cut cut you know they could try and
control the corridor through a military
expansion and thereby cutting off the
the northeast of India the Far East of
India from the rest of the nation that's
what they could dry or they could try
something in arunachal Pradesh to take a
take a bite at tawang for instance you
know Monastery is one of the holiest
sites in Tibetan Buddhism and that's
something the Chinese covet so they
could try and take a bite to tawang or
some other part of the no off of
arunachal Pradesh or they could try
something further in in the ladakh
region in the oxygen region which they
currently illegally temporarily occupy
so there are multiple places that where
they could indulge in a misadventure
maybe even in uttarakhand in this region
right so there are multiple places they
can choose from choose from in order to
indulge Universe Adventure against India
they will calculate where they have the
biggest likelihood of succeeding and
they go try something so that is one
possible scenario right so if there is
indeed a coup the new leader will have
no option but to take some very strong
action in order to justify his Ascension
to power and prove to the Chinese people
into the Communist party that he belongs
in the position of the Paramount leader
of China so if a new leader comes into
play into power that leader is most
likely going to be belligerent and his
actions will be substantially harsher
than those of Xi Jinping Xi Jinping is
playing the long game he wants China to
win by 2050 or so right he wants China
to replace and displace the us as the
global sole superpower by 2050 or or
thereabouts
so he's played the long game a new
leader if he comes into power through a
coup will have to play a very short game
and prove very rapidly that he deserves
to be the leader so then you would see
an unstable China and um you know
unforeseen circumstances could emerge
because if they try and uh they if they
try and take bites at Indian Territory
the Indians will not just sit down and
take it the India is going to fight back
and India is very capable of fighting
back India overall is economically
smaller than China India's economy is
much smaller than China right now
temporarily India's military strength is
less than that of China significantly
yes but if you look at the overall
balance in the Himalayan region India is
in India and China are reasonably well
matched and India has the ability to
make China pay very extremely heavy
price for any misadventure because we
have the Ultimate Weapon we never want
to use that but if the Chinese cross
certain red lines they're gonna pay the
price for that so again that could be
something that the Chinese would find
undesirable unless they are really
stupid so that's what I see happening
these are the possible scenarios I still
feel that the likelihood of a coup
having happened in China is
significantly low most likely what's
happening is that Xi Jinping is
conducting an internal Purge of the
Chinese Communist party and for that he
has gridlocked the country shut down
most of the flights most of the trains
and until this process is done no news
will come out of China and this is the
how efficient and efficacious the
Chinese system is such an enormous
country and no news is coming out of
China we don't know what's happening
inside that's how airtight and
watertight their entire system is no
news leaks out that they don't want the
rest of the world to know so that is
where we are right now obviously the
next few days we'll get more information
and let's see if I turn out to be right
or if I turn out to be wrong but this is
what I feel
okay so uh I re-uploaded a video today
because of what's Happening about the
possibility of a of a coup being likely
in China yeah I said that the China is a
nation that uh that is especially going
to be prone to uh undergoing coups and
lots of people get upset about that
there's so two people here and icon 6754
uh don't you think the same thing
applies to India as well why don't you
talk about that and doesn't the per
capita GDP argument apply to India as
well India's per capita income is
unfortunately less than less than half
of China yes certain things apply to
India but does the overall thing to
apply to India see when when you say
good things about India and you say bad
things about China it somehow it makes
very some people very upset I don't know
why anyhow let me explain why this does
not apply to India there are three
preconditions to a coup how do I know
this you see this book up here this pink
book here can you see that that is a
book called kudeta its author is Dr
Edward ludwak who has been on this
podcast I think Dr Luther wrote this
book as a very young man I think in the
1960s this book this this one that I
have over here it's a 21st century
version of that older book it's still as
relevant today as it was all those years
ago right so there are three
preconditions to work who happening
successfully in a nation and it will
happen successfully only if all three
preconditions are satisfied so what are
the three preconditions for a coup let's
take Nations like India China Pakistan
Pakistan Bangladesh and let's take the
us as well so let's keep these countries
in mind and down now let's talk about
the preconditions of a coup the first
precondition out of three is economic
backwardness
so when you have economic backwardness
in a country you're going to have other
factors that that are emerge out of it
you will have disease you will have
illiteracy you will have a high birth
rate and a high death rate you will have
periodic episodes of hunger famines or
whatever it is droughts no periodic
hunger you're going to have a huge
disparity of income the
majority of the people in a nation will
have very low income and they will be
marginalized
by a very small number of people who
hold all the power and who hold all the
money so there's going to be a huge
income disparity 98 of people will will
be subsisting on let's say 100 rupees a
day or two dollars a day or whatever it
is one dollar a day and the elite the
very small Elite will be living lives
like Millionaires and they will be
living lives of luxury
do you have that in India I think India
is getting more prosperous the people
the per capita GB GDP is rising and the
cost of living is low in India it's not
only about the per capita GDP it's all
about the also about the cost of living
so in some Nations the incomes are low
and the cost of living is very high and
that is what creates incredible distress
in society in India the average income
is rising year after year the per capita
GDP is rising and the cost of living
throughout most of India is still very
very low
so India is indeed India has some
economic backwardness but that is being
worked on the in the nation is rising
and there is no marginalization of the
of the majority by a very small minority
like you have in any Community Society
where the polit bureau very small number
of people who run the Communist Party
who hold all the power they also hold
all the money and everything else is
collectivized and private and that sort
of thing China is not following
Socialism or communism anymore it is a a
capitalist Society an imperial Society
but you do have the marginalization of
the minority of the majority by a very
small minority so the outcome of
economic backwardness is that
the social and economic conditions of
the nation are such that they confine
economic and political participation to
a small fraction of the population
does that is that precondition satisfied
in India in India people are
aspirational people's incomes are
increasing people are able to consume
more buy more things everybody can
participate politically everybody votes
and everybody can actually stand for
election if they want to they have to
figure out the right way of doing it but
it's possible it's open to all so in
India economic and political
participation is not confined to a small
fraction of the population it is not in
China
it's the the it's the various Chinese
billionaires who who rise to the top
because they satisfy certain conditions
laid out by the Chinese Communist party
and so the economic participation is
confined to a small fraction even the
political participation the true
political participation is confined to a
small fraction of the population so
so uh the first precondition of Economic
backwardness and economic and political
marginalization is satisfied in China
but not in India it's also satisfied in
Pakistan it could also
um yeah it's not satisfied in the U.S in
the US everybody can vote and everybody
can can benefit from capitalism so once
again the U.S doesn't satisfy it India
doesn't satisfy it Bangladesh
increasingly doesn't satisfy this
precondition but China satisfies it and
Pakistan certainly satisfies it that's
why China and Pakistan are prone to Coos
what is the second precondition of a
coup succeeding
the second precondition is political
Independence the nation needs to be
politically independent and Dr ludwak in
this book he speaks about the 1956
Hungarian Revolution so in the 1956
Hungarian Revolution the people
who participated in this revolution to
free Hungary from USSR they were able to
take over the Armed Forces of the
country they were able to take over the
police of the country they were able to
secure all the radio stations and all
the communications facilities they did
all that and yet
the revolution failed why did it fail
because the true power in the country
was not in the Hungarian Armed Forces
not the police not the radio stations
not the communications facilities the
true power
was the presence of the Soviet Red Army
inside Hungary and around Hungary this
was a greater source of power to any
government that was supported by Moscow
than any element within the country
right so the control of the Red Army was
in Moscow therefore the therefore the
Hungarian Revolution would have
succeeded only if it had been carried
out from Moscow not from Buddha paste in
Hungary see so that is the deal about
political Independence the nation must
be substantially politically independent
and the influence of external Powers
foreign powers in its internal political
life
must be relatively limited you can never
have complete political Independence and
complete non-interference from outside
inside your country but the interference
and influence of foreign powers must be
substantially
limited and less that is called
political Independence so is India
political independent more or less India
is politically independent right so
therefore a coup cannot really happen in
India is Pakistan politically
independent where there is substantial
interference inside Pakistan
uh from external affectional factors the
Pakistan Army has always been propped up
by external actors first it was the
British then it was the Americans and
now it is the Chinese
so Pakistan does satisfy the
precondition of the coup when it comes
to China
you don't have substantial political uh
interference within China and yet the
structure of the Chinese Communist party
is that you will have political
interference from within the Chinese
Communist party and you will have always
you will always have these various
centers of power that will seek to come
up quietly and grab the the power at the
right time especially the so-called
people's Liberation Army that actually
can act as a major uh factor in in
Chinese politics in India the Army is is
is non-political in China the Army is
very political in Pakistan also the Army
is very political in the U.S the Army is
not political it obeys whatever the
state tells it to do whatever the
president and whoever else runs the
thing it obeys them in India the Army
always obeys the uh Center the the
central government in China the Army is
a major factor it has its own politics
in Pakistan also so that's why once
again China satisfies the precondition
Pakistan satisfy the second precondition
India does not the US does not
Bangladesh also most likely nowadays
does not let's see right and the third
precondition the last final precondition
of a coup is what Dr ludwak calls
organic Unity which means that the
nation must have a political Center if
there are multiple political centers
these must be uh organized and
structured politically not ethnically
right if you have a mono uh
if you have something that is monolithic
if you have a monolithic Nation with
only one ethnicity and only one religion
or whatever on only one ideology then
all even if you have multiple percentage
of political power these are structured
politically not ethnically or
religiously right so in Pakistan there
is only one political Center which is
the Pakistani army
there are no other genuine centers of
political power none whatsoever you have
elections you have state governments but
these are all sham the real power is
just the Pakistani army there is no
other real power any prime minister who
is currently in power is just a puppet
they do what they are told similarly in
China there is only one political Center
the Chinese Communist party and whoever
runs the Chinese Communist party is the
boss there are other political centers
in various uh provinces of China but
these are subsidiary these are also
Chinese political Chinese Communist
Party centers and these are all
subsidiary to the uh polit Bureau so it
has a very clear Center of political
power that's why China and Pakistan once
again satisfy the preconditions of a
coup in India we have a central
government that is to many into to a
large extent in some ways powerless when
it comes to influencing in the various
state governments India we call it the
power of federalism I think it's a it's
a it's not the it's not a good thing
actually to have too much federalism
yeah because that is because the state
the central government sometimes is
powerless to stop the States from doing
certain things you have
a project I am not naming in a state by
the way please understand this I'm not
naming any specific State let's say
you're a project of of uh constructing a
railway corridor from which includes
seven states then you have to go through
a whole process of buying the land
acquiring the land and constructing
everything and so on so forth if certain
States refuse to go over it then you
will not be able to build the real
Corridor through those three or four
states and then the entire project is
ruined right that's one example if you
have certain border states that kind of
have an open border policy and they
allow infiltrators to come in that's
again a huge issue and this is sometimes
this central government may not be in a
position to stop that from happening
because the unless they want to
overthrow the government uh put
president's rule in which case the
Supreme Court will intervene and prevent
this from happening so there are so many
problems in India there are so many
different centers of power these are all
based on languages every state is is
based on language language based states
you have Maharashtra where you have
Marathi you have odisa where you have
odia you have Tamil Nadu which is a
Tamil region you have Karnataka with
kannada speaking people you you have
Punjab with Punjabi speaking people and
so on and so forth so and so forth
everything is linguistically based and
when you have linguist linguistic
divisions you people will also perceive
that to be ethnic divisions even though
we all Indians are the same people so
India is a chaotic country it doesn't
have a political Center a coup can never
ever succeed in India for this precise
reason it's impossible for a coup to
succeed in India the U.S
is not ethnically structured the U.S
actually does satisfy this particular
precondition of a coup right India does
not Pakistan does single
single religion everything else is
immaterial so once again Pakistan has a
political Center it is not structured
ethnically it is structured politically
it's just one religion everything else
is is unacceptable similarly Bangladesh
also satisfies this precondition
and China it's just I mean the Chinese
do have various ethnicities like the
Tibetans whom they have forcibly amalgia
Amalgamated they have the oy girls they
have various other ethnicities like the
the Thai people in the Yunnan Province
and the the Manchu people in Manchuria
which is again illegally next by China
and so on so forth but there is only one
dominant ethnicity which is the Han
Chinese and only one language is allowed
which is the the Mandarin Chinese
language right and so on
so so China is like a monolithic
Nation other ethnicities exist other
nations other languages exist but those
are completely marginalized only one
dominant ethnicity exists which is the
Han Chinese only one language is allowed
and only one ideology is a lot which is
the ideology of the Chinese Communist
party whatever is in uh Vogue right now
so China has a very clear political
Center and it is completely politically
structured all it is just one ethnicity
which makes it a moral monolithic
country and therefore China satisfies
all three preconditions for a coup so
does Pakistan India doesn't satisfy any
of the preconditions of a coup the U.S
satisfies maybe one or two preconditions
but not all
and so on so I hope this detailed
exposition
of the matter sets this question to rest
that why China is way more predisposed
to a coup than most of the Nations and
India simply cannot have a coup that can
succeed I hope that answers the question
thank you very much let's move on to the
next question
okay Arjun and vapov asked the question
uh about the Cyprus issue so what are
your thoughts on Dr jayashankar raising
the Cyprus issue at the unga and what is
the turkey Cyprus issue recently Dr SJ
Shankar directly held talks with the
Turkish foreign minister and
about the Cyprus issue after erdogan
raised the issue of Kashmir in the
United Nations General Assembly all
right
so what is the Cyprus issue the Cyprus
issue is something that goes back a long
time Cyprus is a nation-state in in the
Mediterranean region let's go and look
at the map where's the map here's the
map Batman map
so let's go to the Mediterranean region
do you know where it is we know where
India is I hope yes this is India go
west west west so now now we're in the
Middle East and go further west and you
have uh the Eastern Mediterranean region
right you have Israel you have Lebanon
you have Syria you have uh Anatolia
which is not turkey and south of
Anatolia you have this island called
Cyprus so this was historically a Greek
island yeah it was inhabited by Greeks
for uh for close to 3000 or so years
yeah that's how old Greece is roughly
3000 years so Cyprus is has historically
been a Greek island Greek people of
Greek ethnicity of Greek language Greek
culture inhabited the silent for for a
few thousand years maybe two three
thousand years right uh so this island
came under the occupation of the Ottoman
Empire during the time of the Ottoman
Empire which is the last four five
hundred years uh beginning around the
15th 16th century somewhere around there
yeah
so uh I may have got the dates slightly
wrong please don't quote me on that you
get the rough idea right
so uh Cyprus was under ottoman
occupation later the Ottoman Empire in
the 19th century started becoming really
really weak
and uh eventually Cyprus was made
independent it became a separate nation
typically one things of Cyprus as being
a Greek uh Nation but it's it's a it's
an independent nation it's the Republic
of Cyprus then when was this what was it
in the 1970s or somewhere uh most likely
in the 1970s the Turks invaded Cyprus
now in Cyprus because of the auto
occupation you have two distinct uh it's
no religious groups one is the
traditional ancestral Greek people who
have who speak the Greek language who
practice Greek Orthodox Christianity and
uh yeah and they are Greeks and in the
north part of the island you have about
one third of the population of the
entire Island that uh are converts to
Islam because of the Ottoman occupation
of the place they identify themselves as
Turks and they speak the Turkish
language and practice the religion that
is prevalent in Turkey right which is
Islam so you had this ethnic issue in in
that's left over in many parts of Europe
actually because of the Ottoman
occupation right so in the 1970s the
Turks invaded Cyprus right the invaded
Cyprus and the annexed roughly the
northern one third of Cyprus so if you
look at the uh the map of the island you
can see there's a weird dashed line
which has actually two dashed lines and
there is a no man's land in between and
you can see the capital of Cyprus
Nicosia which is bifurcated roughly
roughly bifurcated by this thing so half
of nicosiah is turkic Turkish half of it
is Greek that's the weird thing and yeah
so that's what happened the Turks took
over uh at least one third of the island
the the Turks occupy this island through
military force and that's what is
happening right now that's what happened
in the 1970s if I'm not mistaken I don't
remember the exact year maybe whatever
I'm not going to give you a year you can
look it up if you are interested
and then various issues started the
Turkish identifying
uh people of Cyprus they started you
know the age-old practice practice of
kidnapping Greek women and forcibly
marrying them off after converting them
the same old thing with those practice
during the Ottoman Empire
there have been I don't know hundreds or
thousands of cases of this happening
over the over the past few decades and
yeah so the aggressors are the Turks and
the victims
are the Greeks the Greek cypriots that
is the Cyprus issue and I think the
entire world recognizes this as a
Turkish aggression and a forcible
Turkish military occupation of a nation
that is not Turkish right I think most
of the world agrees about this so this
is something that Turks have done this
is in contravention of all international
law and so and so forth but they're
holding on to this place because turkey
has is part of NATO and the Americans
are willing to look the other way in
exchange for Turkish cooperation in
other issues right so that is the Cyprus
issue now these Turks especially the Mr
erdogan who fancies himself as the next
ottoman sultan
uh erdogan Mr erdogan is taking uh
turkey in a direction that is completely
which is diametrically opposite to the
vision of Mustafa Kamal Ataturk who is
Ataturk the father of the Turks
found single-handedly forged this nation
of turkey out of the ruins of World War
World War One in World War One the Turks
sided with Germany and they were
defeated and the nation was broken into
pieces it was partitioned into I don't
know multiple Pieces by the Victorious
European allies and uh
refused to accept this he waged a war
against multiple opponents including the
ottoman sultan and he defeated them all
and he carved out an independent nation
of turkey yeah and he envisioned a
progressive modern secular Nation that's
what he sought turkey to be yeah so he
implemented a whole lot of reforms in
Turkey including uh
the abolition of various uh ancient
Customs like the like the whale and the
various uh Arabic influenced dresses the
abolished the the use of the Arabic
script foot uh for the Turkish language
he introduced a certain version of the
Latin script and he sought to make
turkey a prosperous modern Progressive
secular Nation secular in the true sense
of being right so that's what he thought
now and turkey did very well after that
obviously uh turkey was under military
rule for a very long time thanks to uh
thanks to some some encouragement from
the Americans I am sure we can look into
that at a certain point ten but ever
since Mr erdogan took power he has taken
he is he has started taking turkey in
the direction opposite to what Mr what
the great Mustafa Kamal had envisioned
and Turkey
um yeah so there is this internal
conflict happening in Turkey right now
and as a result of his uh of the
direction Mr erdogan is taking turkey in
he has been consistently supporting
Pakistan Pakistan they they uh try to
portray Pakistan and turkey as Blood
Brothers or whatever we want to call it
because of the common religious bond
that they have the majority population
of Turkey as well as Pakistan is Sunni
Muslim right that's what the practice in
Islam so the the Turks
on a geopolitical level try to portray
Pakistan as their blood brother and
pakistanis are they love it the Pakistan
you know the problem with Pakistan is
that they seek a foreign
and the Arabs have this distance
themselves from the Pakistan is saying
the new pakistanis are not Arabs we do
not recognize you as Arabs so the
pakistanis were in search of a new Daddy
because they need a foreign Daddy they
cannot identify as Indians because that
would be terrible so now they are trying
to identify as Turks yeah and the Turks
have kind of encouraged that in the
various Turkish cereals which distort
history are very popular in Pakistan
Pakistan yeah
so that's what's happening so because of
their support for Pakistan the Turks
have been at multiple on multiple
occasions being raising the Kashmir
issue and supporting Pakistan over it so
recently this individual erdogan
uh who looks like Gollum but Styles
himself as the new emperor or new
ottoman Khalif Sultan of turkey he
recently uh apparently raised the
Kashmir issue at the unga United Nations
General Assembly right and that is the
background to what this question is
about so in response to that Dr s Jai
Shankar who is our chief diploma who is
our foreign minister he recently held
talks with the foreign minister of
turkey and at the end of the talks he
announced to the media that he raised
the Cyprus issue with his counterpart
with his Turkish counterpart so the deal
is very simple you gonna raise up the
Kashmir issue we're gonna raise up the
Cyprus issue Cyprus turkey has no
business being in Cyprus it has nothing
to do with them it is not part of turkey
it has never been part of turkey it was
forcibly occupied by the Ottoman Empire
for some time but the people are Greeks
and turkey simply has no business being
there right Kashmir on the other hand
has been part of India for thousands of
years it's an integral part of India
civilization for 10 000 plus years and
you find lots of cultural artifacts in
turkey that prove in in Kashmir the
progress there is no turkic or Turkish
artifact in in Cyprus other than what
they have constructed in the past two
300 years during the Ottoman occupation
so that's why Cyprus is occupied
territory and illegally occupied
territory and if the Turks are gonna try
raising the Kashmir issue we're going to
dredge out the Cyprus issue and we're
gonna make we're gonna speak about it at
all appropriate fora and we're gonna
bring the world's attention attention
back on this and that's going to cost
them diplomatically the Turks so that is
the stands India is taking this is
aggressive diplomacy this is not the
Chinese wolf Warrior diplomacy where you
become all rude and aggressive and use
harsh language and and the harsh body
language this is actually effective
diplomacy you're gonna raise Kashmir
we're gonna raise Cyprus and we you you
are the real aggressors in Cyprus we are
not aggressors in Kashmir so that's the
deal
so that's a very simple message that is
being sent to Turkey we are not no
longer going to sit back and let you do
whatever you want we're going to
retaliate and it's going to cost you so
that's what's happening and I'm very
happy very glad to see The Stance India
is now taking excellent
okay Alka says the Indian rupee has
recently breached the 80 dollar the 80
rupee Mark against the US dollar so one
US dollar is now more than 80 right we
look into that so do you sense any
significant trouble for the Indian
economy
let's take a look uh I would have loved
to see the Deutsche Mark and the French
franc and all that but now it is it's
just the Euro they've destroyed the
European uh various currencies so let's
see where we are at shall we what's
happening
yes we know that the Indian rupee is now
um worth more than 80 rupees
it's not 81. let me put that on the
screen right let's see what the current
situation is and let's take a a one-year
Outlook
so this is something you can see online
anywhere Come on load upload up where is
it yeah yeah there we go so this is a a
chart there are multiple websites that
show you the latest uh status of any any
two currencies and you can see the chart
over one year 10 year million years
whatever you want to see so this is the
one year status of the Indian uh rupee
against the US dollar at exactly 365
days ago the Indian rupee was somewhere
around 73 73 Rupees to the US dollar
today it is at 81.23 right that is where
the Indian rupee is so this is an
increase of 10.2 percent
the Indian rupee has become 10.2 percent
uh it's increased in in price so the US
dollar has gained 10 percent against the
Indian rupee now let's see other
currencies for some proper context shall
we we only keep on harping about India
but let's see what's happening across
the world and then we will have the uh
appropriate context in which to see the
performance of the Indian rupee your
favorite news channels will only talk
about the rupee your favorite media
commentators or geopolitical analysts or
whoever will only talk about the rupee
let's let's see the Euro how is the Euro
doing against the US dollar let's take a
look at the Euro so one year ago 365
days ago the Euro was at 0.85 Euros to
one dollar right today it is at 1.0
zero three one Whatever right so that is
how much the Euro has dropped against
the dollar which is a decrease of 21.6
percent
Indian rupee 10 euro 21.6 let's look at
the pound share with the British pound
let's look at what's happening to the
British pound the British pound one year
ago
was 0.73 pounds to one dollar today it
is at 0.92222 or whatever to one US
dollar that's a drop of 26.3 percent the
U.S pound has been annihilated it's it's
a it's at a 50-year low against the US
dollar the euro is at a 30-year low
against the US dollar let's take a look
at some other currencies let's take a
look at the Canadian and Australian
currencies are worthless I don't care
let's take a look at the en
what's happening to the Japanese Yen one
year ago it was at uh 110 roughly yens
against the dollar right now it's at 143
ends against the US dollar so that is a
drop of 31.6 percent
they have smashed and destroyed the
Japanese Yen that's what the Americans
have done let's take a look at the
Chinese our dear Chinese friends where
are they uh not the Swiss franc that's a
special currency let's look at the
Chinese Yuan
and how the Chinese yuan is faring
against the dollar so one year ago the
Yuan was at 6.46 yuan's per US dollar
right now we're at 7.13 or whatever the
current thing is which is a drop of 10.2
percent the Chinese yuan is performing
exactly
like the Indian rupee 10.2 percent drop
the other nations the other currencies
have been totally annihilated the euro
is at a 30-year low 21.6 Drop the
British pound is at a 50-year low 26
26.3 drop and the Japanese Yen has
dropped 31.6 let's take a look at one
more currency yeah
let's take a look at one more currency
the other currencies are not really
important let's take a look at the
Russian ruble
Whoopsie Daisy what happens here one
year ago it was at 73 rubles per dollar
in uh
in March it went to
135 point something against the dollar
today it is at 57 point something
against the dollar so the ruble has got
stronger by 20.5 percent against the
dollar all other currencies are being
destroyed not the rupee in the U in the
in the in the Yuan but other currencies
are being totally annihilated the ruble
is appreciating look at that that's what
the Russians have achieved
so in the big picture this is what the
Americans have done they have tried to
destroy all the various currencies in
the world the Indian rupee has dropped
only 10 percent the Chinese Yuan has
dropped only ten percent the the euro is
at a 30-year low the the pound the
British pound is at a 50-year low the
Japanese Yen has been annihilated by
more than 30 percent the ruble is
appreciating so India is doing actually
quite well please understand this see
things from a bigger perspective don't
have this narrow vision
all right the Indian rupee is actually
doing well it is not that badly affected
by the various American moves so what
have the Americans been doing how have
they engineered This Global collapse
first of all they have printed
gazillions of dollars worth of paper
currency
when you flood the market with paper
currency it causes inflation it causes
the value of the currency to drop but
then you can always Rectify this by
increasing interest rates which suddenly
makes that currency valuable because if
you buy bonds or whatever in that
currency you're gonna get more interest
so first you flood the market
with paper currency then you raise
interest rates that destroys other
currencies that makes other currencies
less valuable nobody wants to buy that
so the sell of other currencies in the
buy more dollars that's how you can
manipulate the market basic very very
very uh you know School level economics
so that's what the Americans have been
doing but India
whatever we are doing I'm not sure what
the Indian government is doing from the
RBI perspective economic perspective but
whatever India is doing it's working
India's rupee has depreciated by only 10
point something percent 10.2 percent
just like the Chinese Yuan
the Russian Ruble is doing extremely
well the Americans are not able to do
anything about the ruble because they
have pegged the their currency to the
price of gold it's now at the gold
standard nobody can touch that the
Russian Ruble is now a proxy for actual
gold yep
so that is the situation I do not sense
any significant trouble for the Indian
economy we have to be very careful we
have to be very wary of what the
Americans are doing the Americans are
trying to reconfigure the entire world
by these are the done these are
essentially nuclear measures you know
what they're doing flooding the world
economy with trillions of dollars of
currency notes paper money and then
increasing interest rates to to make the
dollar again more valuable which
destroys other other currencies that's
what they're trying to do so the Indian
Rupees is reasonably steady it's doing
well yeah obviously we've dropped 10
like the Chinese Yuan but not to the
extent that other currencies have been
totally annihilated so we are doing okay
but yes the government will have to keep
a very close watch on All American
actions and we have to take appropriate
measures to ensure the stability and
integrity of our currency in our economy
so we are we are on the right path
that's what I would say
okay Vishal says the Russian Federation
will hold a referenda in the occupied
areas of occupy the liberated tomato
tomato potato potato okay in the areas
of luhansk Donetsk hersson and japoresia
does that mean that this was the core
territory that Russia wanted to Annex
great question so let's take a look at
the map because the map is our best
friend we love the map on this channel
where's the map
where is the map
here is the map
right so let's take a look at the
territories that have either been
occupied or liberated depending on whom
you ask so we have Ukraine over here
which will soon I don't know be called
with another name I don't know so you
have a luhansk do you see where you
Lohan says this here is luhansk it's a
city and it's also an oblast which is
that which is you could you could call
it a province or a state then you have
Donetsk which is over here so this is
the donbass region essentially right
then you have the uh let's zoom in a
little bit more you have uh come on Zoom
okay here we are you have her son which
is north of the Crimea Peninsula which
is already under Russian control and
then you have zaporizia which is over
here which is further north of uh north
east of Herson and west of Donetsk right
so this is the oral region that Russia
controls more or less right now they
also control the Crimea Peninsula yes
and they also hold her son so they will
be now uh they may be in the process of
doing it right now holding a referendums
or referenda in this region and that is
obviously the Prelude to an official
reintegration of these territories with
the Republic of Russia or you could call
it annexation you could call it whatever
you want to call it right so all these
these parts of Ukraine will now sooner
or later become become officially
Russian territory so the the map in
Google will not change because the
Americans won't allow that but that's
how it's going to be that's what the
grounder realities are going to reflect
so what does this mean
does it mean that this was the core
territory the Russians wanted to Annex
the Russians obviously wanted to Annex
this territory first because that's
where most of these regions have Russian
majority people who speak Russian as
opposed to Ukrainian people who identify
as ruse Russians as opposed to ukraini
ukrainians right so yes the Russians did
want to uh
uh Annex or reintegrate these
territories with the Russian Nation so
that's I think the first objective yeah
so they're gonna soon most likely
achieve this they're gonna be some
people will call it a sham election
referendum it doesn't matter the
Russians have boots on the ground they
control these territories now they will
go through this process and that will
lead to the uh integration of these
territories with Russia
I'm not sure if it is the only
objective of the of the Ukraine war of
the of the uh Special Operation that
Russia has done in Ukraine uh I think
the actual long-term objective is to
once end for all end the threat that
Ukraine poses to Russia Ukraine had the
largest land Army in in Europe apart
from the Russian army their army was
stronger than the armies of France and
Germany put together they had an
enormous tank force which is now gone
right
their tank force has been decimated the
Americans are now pushing in these you
know uh Second Hand t-72 tanks into
Ukraine because all the Ukrainian tanks
have been destroyed and even those U.S
given t-72 tanks are also most mostly
gone now and therefore therefore now
they are being forced to donate older
tanks like t52 or whatever tanks to the
ukrainians those will also be soon gone
so the Russians are slowly but steadily
ending destroying annihilating the
Ukrainian War Machine it's going to be
neutralized once and for all and if
there is any escalation the Russians can
totally devastate Ukraine
till today they have not even used the
Air Force you don't understand how
potent the Russian military is yes they
are right now mobilizing some some uh
reservists or conscripts or whatever
which is great it doesn't mean that the
Russians are desperate they are
mobilizing
trained forces trained soldiers or
semi-trained soldiers who will be
inducted rapidly into the Russian
military most of these will come in from
the uh
from which region of Russia the the
Caucasus region of Russia uh the
Dagestan region and and what's the other
place called The Dagestan region and uh
yeah the the the the Crimean sorry the
Caucasus region of Russia
uh so that's what they're doing and they
they will be able to raise I don't know
roughly half a million stronger new
forces right so they they are not
desperate they are doing things
systematically in a planned manner I'm
sure this is something they had also
planned
so uh
so I think the Russian long-term
objective is to neutralize completely
the Ukrainian fighting machine the
Ukrainian War Machine the Ukrainian
military the Americans are pushing in
arms and ammunition they are pushing an
older and older tanks now because uh
they've run out of Tanks to to give the
the ukrainians unless they start giving
them American tanks which will be of
significant escalation it won't go down
with Russia and that will lead to
consequences and repercussions
so the Ukrainian military is being
slowly eroded and decimated it will
I don't know in in some time
mathematically speaking it will cease to
exist as a fighting force the Americans
are providing them with various missiles
and things how long does that last the
Russians have clearly been planning for
this war for a decade or more it must
have been in the plans for much longer
than that
maybe ever since Mr Putin came to power
right so that's what's happening
currently in Ukraine do you see all
kinds of reports in the western media
that the Russians are losing they have
been saying this from day one look at
the maps look at where the the the uh
referendums are happening you can see
that that tells you what territories the
Russians control they control at least
one fourth of Ukraine some battles
happen some territories gained and lost
it's like chess moves yeah look at the
overall chess game from start to end
whenever it ends don't look at
individual chess moves
you know you may make a big sacrifice in
chess a queen sacrifice it looks like a
disaster but that actually sometimes
helps you if you know what you're doing
to win the chess game so this is a
long-term chess game you know these
moves are done tactical moves are done
it doesn't mean anything in the long run
or it may mean something in the long run
so that's what's happening in Ukraine
and let's keep we will on this channel
in this program we're gonna keep a long
term eye on the Ukraine conflict and
we're gonna keep on speaking about this
periodically as in when something of
importance something of import happens
all right so that's where we are as of
today my dear friends
okay again by Vishal how will Vladimir
Putin cope with his biggest headache the
Aging population of Russia
this is a good question once again uh
Russia's population is in indeed aging
the the uh fertility rates in Russia
have dropped way below our replacement
levels I'm not sure what the numbers are
you can look it up but we know that the
population is declining the population
is aging and that is indeed a long-term
problem for Russia you know they need to
do something about this and we have to
ask ourselves why do they'll do such
things happen why do certain Nations uh
undergo such declines
it typically happens when the cost of
living becomes High and the salaries or
your income the median income per
individual or per family drops
so when the cost of living is very high
and your income doesn't quite support
that it becomes really hard to have more
kids because how will you support those
kids and their education and everything
you would want to give to your children
that's why some most parents in such
situations they decide to have fewer
kids some decide not to have kids at all
yep see what's happening in in Japan see
what happens in China China it was like
State policy only one child in Russia
there's no such thing but what happened
in Russia was in the last 30 years was
close to a disaster after the
disintegration of the USSR the Russian
economy was deliberately systematically
destroyed by Boris elsin Boris was most
likely doing this at the behest of his
Masters in the west he was a darling of
the western media and the Western
Nations right for for good reason it was
implementing their policies of
destroying the Legacy and the economy of
the that the USSR had built over seven
or I don't know how many decades you
know close to close to seven decades
Boris and systematically destroyed
Russia's great Industries and everything
the Russians had built up and and
everything the Russian people had saved
and and contributed to the economy of
the USSR so because Russia's economy was
almost destroyed inflation was
skyrocketing the the prices of daily
everyday basic Commodities were
skyrocketing the the Russian Nation went
to close went through close to two
decades of absolute misery and that
obviously will have a consequence of
people having less children now things
may be looking better now maybe slowly
the the birth rate the fertility rate
may rise but that's gonna take time and
the impact of these two lost decades is
going to be significant right so there's
the population is aging the average age
is rising there are fewer births per per
fertile women or whatever the the
statistic is
so how does Russia deal with this the
Russians will have to deal with this by
by improving their economy that's that's
a long-term view you improve your
economy you make the median income rise
and you bring the cost of living down
people will automatically start having
more children if people are happier if
the nation is doing well you
automatically have more uh have a higher
fertility rate but obviously it's not
gonna be like the impoverished Nations
where the cost of living is low and the
medium income is also low where you can
afford to have 15 kids some Nations have
this right so it's not going to be like
that but hopefully it goes above 2.1
which is the replacement rate but in the
short term what can the Russians do
in Russia there are certain regions of
Russia which have above fertility above
replacement uh fertility rates TFR total
fertility rates once again
I just now spoke about the Caucasus
region yes
so uh the Caucasus region whether it is
whether it is Dagestan this region has a
significantly high fertility rate which
is significantly I believe higher than
2.1 per woman
so these are the Muslim republics of
Russia these republics right now are
providing
the bulk of the soldiers that are
participating in the uh in the Ukraine
intervention you know there have been
special detachments that have been
raised from grozny in chechnya that have
gone and served their nation in the
Ukraine conflict and uh yeah so
if you if you look at a hundred soldiers
participating from Russia you will have
these regions that are currently being
over represented right
so uh the birth rates are very good very
healthy in in chechnya in Pakistan in
the Caucasus region and uh yeah so
that's where we are so that could be a
solution to the Russian uh aging
population problem the replacement rate
in fertility crisis and some analysts
have projected that in the next 30 to 50
years by 2050 or so Russia could be
about 30 percent of the Russian
population could uh reside in the
Caucasus region you know and obviously
that will have certain cultural effects
and all that religious effects but
that's how it is so there are short-term
Solutions there are long-term Solutions
what Mr Putin wants to do well Mr Putin
is already in his late 60s early 70s so
he may have I mean you know eventually
he will have to hand over power to a
successor so hopefully somebody he
elects or selects or the Russian people
said whatever it is whatever the
mechanism is and most likely it's going
to be that next person the successor's
headache in the long run but right now
Mr Putin will have to do something about
it which could involve taking steps to
ameliorate the economic situation in
Russia
that's the deal
rishabh says why is America still
supporting India to the to be uh UNSC
U.N security Council permanent member
even though India opted out of a certain
uh pillar of the ipef the indo-pacific
economic Forum what are your views on
Chinese government officials calling out
west media to get their colonial mindset
quoting a post about India UK GDP
comparison okay let me answer the first
question I'm not sure what the Chinese
have said the Chinese talk about
everything doesn't matter
uh why is the U.S supporting India
uh for the UNSC permanent membership
is America supporting India a few throw
away words in a few statements do not
constitute support my dear friends I
have been saying this for the past more
than a year words are meaningless I
don't know why Indians pay so much
attention to words words are threw away
things you can say a million words that
and you can go back on your words
anytime you want that's how it works in
geopolitics in politics in diplomacy
words are tools to be used and thrown
some are used tactically some are you
strategically and some are used in a
matter of policy and so on the Americans
make this do this lip service to India
we support India's attention to U.N
security Council permanent member have
they taken any actual steps to reform
the UNSC even One initial step of the
taken they've done no such thing it's
all empty words no action no action
whatsoever this U.S support
of India to be a UNSC permanent member
is lip service it's words empty words
they do not want India to ascend in any
way anywhere
they do not want to make the same
mistake with India which they did with
China they aided and abetted and midwife
China's rise to Global power status
China was at the same level as India
extremely
poor economy an impoverished broken down
Nation the Americans aided and abetted
the rise of China to a great power
status not superpower but great power
status economically and militarily and
diplomatically and geopolitically the
Americans made this major mistake they
misunderstood China the miscalculated
they thought if China becomes prosperous
it will become a democracy how silly how
stupid were the
um where initially Nixon and uh what was
his minions named Kissinger right
and then the U.N State Department
officials they made this massive mistake
they will not repeat that mistake with
India they will not allow they do not
seek India to rise
they do not seek to see India rise in
any way they want India to remain where
it is today as a middle power a middle
economy and a middle uh military power
and with a small sphere of influence in
in the Indian subcontinent region that's
all they hope India will ever be if
India becomes a permanent member of the
UNSC is gonna it's gonna catapult India
to the great power status India is still
not a great power India is still a
middle power India is a potential future
great power and the Americans don't want
that to happen they want the world to
remain chaotic and they want a bipolar
world with China as the bad guy and U.S
is a good guy they don't want another
good guy in India in India it's hard to
portray India as a bad guy no matter
what you do so India will then become a
good guy if India is a major power and
they don't want another good guy to be
around so that's the deal the American
whatever support they're giving that's
just lip service they have taken no
actions to reform the UNSC they've done
nothing so I don't know why people keep
believing this I just don't get it how
many times do I have to say this please
understand words are meaningless words
are empty only actions matter
okay
Vlada the impeller says I was wondering
if it's possible for that our external
affairs minister
could be the successor of Modi ji in
2029 elections because he's making a lot
of noise noise
in geopolitics he knows how to represent
the nation at International platforms
the nation also seems to like him and we
don't see any other option other than
yogiji is the successor to the PM Modi
all right
if you are a good Diplomat you're great
at talking diplomatically and
representing the nation in the
international sphere does it mean that
you will be a good National level
politician
diplomacy is very different from
politics a diplomat can be selected or
chosen based on a certain set of skills
those that set of skills has nothing to
do with being good at politics you can
be a brilliant Diplomat and it doesn't
mean they're going to win elections in a
national election
politics is the game of power it's a
Game of Thrones like they say power is a
very mysterious ephemeral substance very
few people understand what power what
constitutes power diplomats understand
power they understand power at Global
geopolitical scales and they know how to
put forth a good Diplomat knows how to
put forth his or her nation's agenda and
you know
and and joust and why diplomatically
with other nations and their
representatives and engage with the
stakeholders and powerful people in
other nations at various levels that's
what diplomats do it doesn't mean that a
diploma can come back to his Nation or
her Nation stand for election in a
popular election and win the support of
the masses even if they can win an
election and become become an MP does it
mean that they will be able to
play the political game and Governor the
support of the entire party it's very
difficult diplomacy is a whole different
kettle of fish and politics is a whole
different thing I do not see Dr s Jai
Shankar uh even trying for this I don't
think that's what Dr shrinker wants his
life's mission is in diplomacy that's
what his core strength is and he's
really good at that I think he's right
now as of 2022 are the most impactful
diploma in the whole world why would he
give that up for
for for the for the game of politics
does it make sense
politics is dirty game there are
allegations counter allegations there is
slander people try to paint you with
various brushes it's it's a very it's a
whole different kind of thing and not
everybody is built for that very few
people have thick skin required to
succeed in politics and obviously the
political skills needed to you know
play The Balancing Act and and and
Garner power it's very very different I
do not see Dr jaishankar even wanting to
be an actual politician he's currently
an MP from the rajya Sabha right the
Raja Sabha is is a whole different thing
it's not the Lok Sabha which is where
the popular elected representatives of
the nation go the Raja Sabha is a whole
different thing let's um it's a kind of
more of selection than election you know
if you have the right support from the
right political party
so I do not see Dr s Jason got even
attempting
to be an active politician in the Lok
Sabha I think Dr Ezra Shankar his life's
Mission and his his
objective is to serve India
geopolitically as India's top Diplomat
however long uh the Prime Minister and
the leadership of the nation would like
that to be and since he's doing is doing
he's doing a great job uh
that's good for the nation what I would
also like and I would hope that Dr
Esther achieves during his tenure is a
significant Reformation of the Indian
foreign Services of the ifs Indian
Foreign Service we need to augment the
service we currently have less than 2
000 total diplomas which is ridiculous
considering the kind of Engagement India
should have with the world we need to
have at least ten thousand fifteen
twenty thousand diplomats from a variety
of of fields you know diplomats who
specialize in various sectors of the
economy and Science and all that that
would be a great thing so we would like
to see that sort of thing happen that
would make India engage effectively and
to its true potential with the rest of
the world so we need to see we would I
would like to see an augmentation of the
ifs and hopefully I I hope that Dr
jayashankar can achieve something in
that regard any kind of reform in any
bureaucratic core is going to meet with
a lot of resistance because if you have
to 1700 diplomats and you and usually
we're going to bring in 10 000 more
those 1700 diplomas they will feel that
their privileged position is going is
now going to erode the way it's going to
be threatened so they may try to resist
that any change is going to be resisted
by the internal stakeholders those who
believe that they have certain
Privileges and they will lose the
privilege so it takes strong leadership
to effect any change of this sort I hope
that Dr Ezra Shankar in in tandem with
the Prime Minister Modi will be able to
reform the ifs and make it the larger
force that India as a nation needs to
have and deserves to have so that's what
I would like to see I do not see Dr
Shankar trying to be an active
politician politician and try to rise to
power I don't I don't see that happening
we focus on the UK on France and Germany
but not much focus on ties with Italy
what to do relations with Italy mean has
to do with India currently and well
Italy be a major player in the current
geopolitics are
so what about Italy what is Italy do to
do with geopolitics is Italy
a major geopolitical player
so to understand whether Any Nation is a
major geopolitical player you have to
look at certain factors number one how
big is the economy Italy has a small
economy not very large how big is the
military Italy military is insignificant
it has a certain military but uh
it's it's not it's not something to
write home about right so economically
nothing great no great progress Italy
doesn't have that many resources to
build a massive economy right it economy
doesn't have a massive military for for
certain reasons that have something to
do with Mussolini and World War II
and most importantly the Italy
government and the Italy Constitution
could have been written by external
actors or have been influenced by
external actors which means the
English-speaking winners of World War II
and you have to also understand that
Italy is also like Germany and Japan
under permanent U.S occupation which
means that Italy is an occupied Nation
no matter how nice it looks there are
permanent U.S military bases on Italian
territory since the end of the second
world war which means in Italy is not a
free state which means Italy does not
have an independent foreign policy when
you don't have an independent foreign
policy foreign policy you are not
an independent geopolitical player so
small economy small military uh occupied
by a foreign power and no independent
foreign policy that means that Italy is
insignificant we don't need to take
Italy very seriously and I apologize to
any dear Italian friends who are
watching I am just telling what I see I
have nothing against the people of Italy
Italy was once a great nation it was the
Roman Empire
yes Roman Empire great Empire it held a
significant portion of Europe and North
Africa and parts of the Middle East
including the the judaic regions in
Syria and so on so forth yeah okay even
parts of Western Arabia so up to some
extent and so on once great today
reduced to nothing less almost nothing
less or reduced to almost insignificance
so Italy the Italian people are a great
people wonderful people they have a
great history wonderful culture great
landscape great climate great food and
all that yes and great gelato
wonderful players but but
so when it comes to Europe and India
ties it's it's with good reason that we
don't really talk about Italy because
this is the situation in Italy someday
they'll be able to free themselves of
the foreign occupation and become
independent again
and maybe in the future someday they
will have a new Roman Empire or whatever
but that's where we are right now so
that is the situation with Italy nothing
significant so and when it comes to
Italy's relations with India well um
nothing significant that I can think of
can you think of something I can't think
of anything significant
um they did some Italians did uh you
know private citizens I heard they were
indulging in smuggling of artifacts you
know Indian uh cultural artifacts out of
India you know yes uh idols and more
things of gods and goddesses stolen from
temples and things like that that was
being smuggled into Europe into the Art
Market why are Italy at some point in
time I'm not sure if it's still there so
I'd heard some reports about that I'm
not sure who that was but that was there
and then you had the very annoying
incident where Italian Marines
on an Italian warship fired at Indian
fishermen and killed one or two of them
those Marines I think they were arrested
and I don't know what happened to the
case afterwards but yeah so they they
seem to have not a very nice attitude
when it comes to India so one does see
some some patterns like that emerge but
overall I like Italy a wonderful place
nice culture good the music a good food
the Pizza Pasta gelato
and so on and they seem to have some
influence on the Americans when it comes
to vendettas in the the gangster movies
and all that so yeah good fun place but
geopolitically insignificantly
okay Vape up says your thoughts does
India urgently need a new National
Security advisor
what an incredible question
why would India need a new National
Security advisor
I think we've got one of the best
National Security advisors you could
ever hope for somebody with an
incredible track record
somebody who has done and achieved so
much in much of which we may never know
or not know for many years because it is
still classified the guy has done so
much
he lived undercover in an elimination
called Pakistan
for several years right as an operative
as an intelligence operative he may have
lived undercover in other parts
of some of some of our uh beloved
favorite neighboring countries
undercover that he understands
intelligence he understands how
statecraft Works he understands how
National Security threats work he
understands things at a much deeper
level than we can even imagine
he understands every single threat that
India faces internal and external
internal and external all that why would
we want to replace him with somebody
else why why on Earth
I hear a certain
Rumblings from various quarters saying
that he is this and he is that
I am very clear about this Mr Ajit doal
is the best NSA we have had in in in my
memory yeah and you know
do you know what is the number one
attribute a successful spy master or a
successful NSA should have
they should appear harmless they should
appear
they should be either invisible or they
should appear to be completely harmless
sometimes they should appear to be
confused always give the wrong
impression when you are able appear to
be you should appear to be unable when
you are strong you should appear to be
weak when you are capable you should
appear to be incapable when you are
focused you should appear to be chaotic
these are the principles of warfare
these are the principles of State
Graphics that are principle
all geopolitics all Warfare all state
craft is based on the art of deception
so said
foreign
you should not advertise what you are
doing
as an essay you should never advertise
what you're doing keep it quiet keep it
quiet when you appear in public make
some random statements about various
things and don't show the world what you
are actually doing
one thing I have noticed over the past
seven eight years or however long it has
been is that we don't really know what
Mr Ajit dewal is doing
which is great which excites me what is
Mr ajidual up to and what is the
security apparatus up to I remember in
the very initial days of the of of the
NDA government in 2014 2015 there were
all these various hackathons in the
country Mr Modi also attended some of
these you know young students college
level students and all participating in
hackathons trying to solve difficult
hacking problems coding problems and
then those hackathons kind of
disappeared what was that all about
was it a talent recruitment scheme for
various activities that we should not
know about and so on so my point is
whatever is happening
should be kept Under Wraps we have so
many problems in India external enemies
internal enemies that the threat of the
2.5 front war that General bipin Road
spoke about it always looms against us
and we need a very strong and silent and
invisible security apparatus to deal
with this
and it's best it is kept quiet right so
Mr Ajit Doyle does not need to advertise
what he is doing and whoever is
speculating that he is whatever I don't
know what people are speculating I
completely disagree with them I don't
know who's saying what I am not naming
anybody or pointing fingers at any
specific person I don't know what's
what's being said I hear that people are
saying various things about him well um
I disagree completely right so that's my
view
on uh Mr ajidol I think he is the best
person for the job and I totally support
him
Rahul says says you once said that the
internal politics of a country
determines how it will behave
geopolitically yes I have said this then
will it be right to say that since China
is a one-party Nation it seeks a
unipolar world the USA is a two-party
state it seeks a bipolar World India is
a multi-party system it seeks a
multi-polar world if this is true then
how can we say that Russia seeks a
multiple world even though it's a
one-party single party Nation
incredible uh out um incredible question
very interesting Insight I personally
had not thought about this India is a
multi-party state we seek a multi-polar
world uh China is a one-party Nation it
takes some unipolar world the US is a
two-party State just one step above a
dictatorship so it seeks a bipolar World
interesting interesting interesting the
French also have multi-party system they
seek a multi-polar world the Russians
what do they really seek
what do the Russians really seek uh
Russia is no longer a great
economic power and Russia is you know it
may be a one-party state or whatever it
may be a dictatorship for all intents
and May and and measures all that but it
is a multi-ethnic nation
Russia is a multi-ethnication you have
the roost people the Russian origin
people you have the people who identify
as tatars you're the people of the
Caucasus the pakistanis the chechens you
have various other ethnicities that live
in Russia you have the Far East of
Russia where you have people of various
other people of turkic ethnicity you
have people who have uh illusion or or
Siberian ethnicity and so much more it's
a it's a mixed bag it's a Melting Pot of
cultures it's a very long elongated
Nation across Northern Eurasia so even
though it's kind of a one-party State
it's a very multi-ethnic Nation
so maybe that's why it seeks this way
and we don't really know in the long run
what the long game is if you if you
study the the pronouncements and
writings of Mr Alexander dugin who's
whose daughter was recently very
unfortunately assassinated so if you
study his geopolitical writings he uh
he says that Russia should aspire to
create a unified kind of uh nation that
encompasses much of Europe right so he
essentially says that Russia should
conquer many parts of Europe and maybe
not other parts of Eurasia but yeah so
there is a kind of in order to uh
strengthen and secure Russia's long-term
National Security so there does seem to
be this Vision that is
quasi-imperialistic that is certainly
expansionistic right and Russia does
also seek a warm water ports typically
it's it's always coveted Iranian
territory yeah sometimes Turkish
territory and recently they even thought
of Pakistan at some points in time maybe
maybe I think it was a Vladimir the
zirinovsky who said that we should
invade and Conquer Pakistan in order to
gain access to the warm Seas of the
Indian Ocean and so on so there is an
element of expansionism in Russian
geopolitical uh
in the geopolitical output Outlook
Russia if you look at the past few
centuries Russia has been an
expansionist state
so when you are an expansionist State
then you will possibly have uh
unipolar worldview or maybe a bipolar
worldview multi-polar worldview may not
be go very well with an expansionist in
a largely expansionist nature so yeah
it's it's not all set in stone it is in
maybe this is what you the question is
that's been asked here it's it's a very
interesting Insight it may also be a
very interesting coincidence yeah
I would say that if India becomes very
powerful in the future maybe in 50 years
the the political system could change
completely take a completely one third
one 360 degree turn 180 degree turn
right that could happen if India becomes
more powerful than China which is
possible not today not next week but in
the next 34 years it's possible if India
plays its cards right in that case India
may also seek a bipolar or unipolar
World anything can happen
think about someone like chandragupta
maurya did he seek a multi-polar world
absolutely not think about someone like
kanishka the great ready seek a multiple
reward no no no no he wanted to conquer
the whole world what did uh
uh what's his name chandragupta the
first of the Gupta Empire he sought
continuous expansion what did uh what
did some of the Gupta seek he sought
continuous expansion these are not
multi-polar World Views when you are
capable of Conquering the world you seek
a unipolar world so it all depends on
where you are right now right now if you
are a middle power you will want for now
a multipolar world once you ascend to
the great power status you may see a
seek a bipolar world when you become a
superpower you may want a unipolar world
it depends on what your station and your
status is so that's how I see this
oh this is a question from Instagram for
once I've taken a question from
Instagram and I don't remember who it is
but yeah I think the person who sees it
will recognize it so the question is
where we sarathan Dharma or our original
Hindu beliefs were they about keeping
the women down just to produce kids and
for pleasure yeah where women treated as
objects and and as Commodities where was
original Hinduism about keeping women
down and using women for kids and for
for producing children for pleasure or
was it the Mughal Invasion that changed
Indian Society having five husbands is
not looked upon as the same as Lord
venkatesh having uh two wives right so
yeah this is the question I get often
what was the true status of women in
Indian Society I mean today if we think
about draupati we find it very strange
she had five husbands how terrible oh my
goodness terrible terrible but uh a king
or a God or a deity having multiple
wives it's it's totally normal and
Powerful part of the course so how did
these attitudes appear in Indian Society
we see the whole world from where we are
today
what we are today is the result of 1000
years of foreign occupation roughly 1000
Years first turkey then then various
Europeans especially the British and
they
remodeled our society to a very large
extent so what was the true original
status of women in India Society so the
foundational text cultural uh text of
India and religious texts of India is
the rig Veda the oldest literature known
to humanity the rig Veda the rigveda is
a collection of hymns divided into into
various sections and books and all that
right
if you examine the hymns of the rigveda
you find that there are there are hymns
written by more than 20 more than
possibly 30 women Scholars
women's Scholars what are the names lopa
mudra who was the the wife of of Rishi
agastya you had lopamudra you had a lady
called gargi you had a lady called
maitri you had a lady called Aditi Gosha
anusuya some of the names I can recall
right now these ladies these great
female Scholars composed many of the
hymns of the red Veda can you think of
any cultural or religious text anywhere
in the world which is to a large extent
composed by women
the most sacred the holiest religious
text that we have in Indian civilization
the rigveda it is to a large extent
composed by women by women Scholars
women who Rose in the scholarly scale
above 99 of men maybe 99.9 percent of
men that's how great they were that's
how accomplished they were so more than
20 no maybe more than 30 women
uh
composed many of the verses they
contributed to the to the verses of the
rigveda that's one example of what was
the status of women in the very early
primordial Indian Society the rigveda is
it represents the oldest known stratum
of Indian society that goes back many
many many thousands of years right
what about other phases of Indian
Society so once again let's go back to
the rig Veda there was this this lady
Warrior maybe a queen whose name was
vishpala
she was a warrior she fought in a battle
she fought Wars right and she was not
simply a commander telling people and
Men what to do she fought herself and
how do we know she fought she lost a leg
in a battle and then she was
she was given a prosthetic leg this is
the first record in human history the
oldest record of in human history of a
prosthetic limb
so this queen vishpala she fought in a
war she lost a leg and she was able to
survive that incident the bleeding was
stanched and she was equipped with a
prosthetic leg and she went back and
continued the war
does this indicate a society in which
women are downtrodden is that what it
looks like to you
right then let's go to the ramayan eat
up
one of the wives yes the king of
ayodhya dasharat had I don't know T
Vibes yeah terrible how how patriarchal
three wives well one of his wives was KK
who is not a very nice lady we don't
like her very much because of all the
political machinations she did
fought in a battle with her husband
her husband got injured she saved his
life and she even won the battle for him
right and in exchange for this
incredible Act of bravery and Valor
dashrath told her that whatever you want
at any point in time in your life if you
ask me if you asked me to Grant you a
wish I will
without question Grant you whatever you
want and she used that in the future uh
to ensure that Lord Rama was forced into
Exile by his father right and he was
Lord Rama was supposed to be the Crown
Prince but he was sent into Exile by his
father and his father
had given his word to to his wife that
he would honor whatever uh wish she
asked for and that's the pound of Flesh
she extracted and that's why she's one
of the villains of the Mahabharata but
this lady fought in a war she fought in
a battle she was side by side with her
husband on The Chariot her husband got
injured Gravely injured he was unable to
continue fighting she took on the mantle
of the warrior she fought she won and
she not only won she saved her husband's
life that's a warrior lady does that
indicate does this indicate a society in
which women are downtrodden and all that
yeah then you have other examples in
much much more recent history you have
the great solanki Queen nayaki Devi who
defeated the whichever who was it Gori I
always mix those two up Gori and gaznavi
it's like
okay it was one of these guys I always I
always no matter how many times I try to
remember memorize I get the two mixed up
gory and gaznavi so she defeated one of
these two monsters
in the Battle of kashada or whatever you
call it in uh in southern Rajasthan
yeah
and it's it's the same guy who fought
against Johan he first lost and then won
gory right gory most likely Gori so Nike
Devi
she was the queen regent which means
that she was a ruling the nation or her
kingdom on behalf of her son who was
still a minor he was still a child so he
was the soon to be king but as as long
as it was a minor and and not of age she
was ruling on his behalf and then there
was this Invasion from this guy this
monster gory most likely and she led her
Army into battle and she inflicted a
massive defeat upon this Invader
Maharani Devi a lady
right then you have other examples
in in turunado right she fought her she
spent her entire life fighting the
Portuguese Invaders and she defeated
them she came out on top every time
great lady a warrior lady the Maharani
of jhansi what about her we know what
she did we know our sacrifice for the
nation she fought the British and they
killed her
so does this look like a a culture a
civilization that oppresses women
and all that
and uh
eventually what happened in the past
1000 years is that a foreign various
foreign influences came into India in
India Society was gradually destroyed
distorted it stopped functioning the way
it is supposed to function that the way
it was designed to function in all kinds
of social ills and and problems crept
into society Indian Society slowly
slowly gradually gradually slowly
steadily inch by inch they came into
Indian Society because the society was
not able allowed to function the way it
was supposed to function right for
instance you had this tradition let's
talk about Kalinga Orissa you had this
tradition called the Mahari dance
tradition Mahari the word Mahari comes
from mahanari great lady so these were
ladies who would dance in temples dance
was the form of Devotion to the gods it
was on par with yoga various forms of
yoga yoga Raj yoga and so on so forth
right and this is something I I learned
from a lady whom I've had a podcast with
which will soon be coming out
so uh
later what happened is that this dance
form was corrupted and it was used by
the invaders for entertainment and
that's why the perception of society
changed and they started regarding any
dance form in which a woman performs as
something that is uh not very nice right
and then that that's how all these
various distortions started creeping up
into Indian Society women were forced to
start covering their faces and bodies
which was never the case in Indian
Society for thousands of years because
the foreign occupiers regarded women as
pieces of meat and that's why it became
tradition for women to be shut down shut
away in the in the houses just to save
you know their integrity
and then these these things then became
codified in Social
traditions and that's why you have
especially in Northern India a very
oppressive Customs when it comes to
women it was done for the safety it
became part of tradition over hundreds
of years you know so
think about it this way
when you have a company
we know that Steve Jobs founded this
Apple company right somewhere in the
1980s or something whatever date it was
whatever year it was this company was a
brilliant company it came up with very
Innovative products yeah the Lisa PC and
it essentially brought personal
Computing into into the real world
it was a path breaking company a
brilliant brilliant company it was doing
very well until there was an internal
coup in the company and Steve Jobs was
thrown out of his own company and
somebody else took over and after they
took over for nearly a day I don't know
how long that phase was but they ran
Apple into the ground Apple the Apple
computer company went nearly bankrupt
then Steve Jobs comes back he comes back
into the picture and he again revives
The Fortunes of Apple company of apple
and today apple is one of the greatest
and largest and most profitable uh and
most valuable companies in the whole
world so that period let's say a decade
whatever it was let's say a decade that
Apple company nearly got destroyed who
was responsible for the horrible
performance of of Apple was it the
employees or was it the leadership
it was the leadership the leadership
destroyed the company through their
policies similarly when you have a
country like India a civilization like
India subcontinent which is ruled by
foreigners and if everything goes wrong
in India whom will you blame the
employees you mean the citizens or the
leadership the the oppressors who are
ruling the country think clearly and
logically you always blame the victims
you always blame the victims you never
look at who has done all this this is
the deal all right so India has never
been this horrible patriarchy patriarch
patriarchal misogynistic oppressive
society and culture the way your
teacher's portrait
India was the most open
and and in society and the best Society
for the men right women were defied
nowhere else will you see this so that's
the deal and I hope that
answers the question yes
okay this is
surname you have the T you have taken
the name of one Parsi family and set
them up as an example blah blah blah
long long long long long thing
um what is the various the synthias and
the gay acquires who are maharashtrians
buttered up the British the various
Rajasthani rulers wives smoked and wore
French chiffons where bunchems with the
British each Community took advantage
for themselves that's why we had to
fight for independence and so on so
forth and please please do your research
well before you point a finger at a
community
um
I don't think I have first of all let's
address the question of of my surname
being a Parsi surname
friends uh
um escape with their life from from
Persia and come to India about 11 1200
years ago right after the Arabian
occupation of Persia and and the
horrific atrocities they perpetrated on
on Persia right recently there was a
tweet from Dr neeraj Rai which he
pointed to a certain study scientific
study which says
you know Dr neeraj has appeared on a
podcast in on this channel he's one of
India's one of the world's foremost
genetic researchers Dr neeraj Rai Dr
neeraj recently you can look up his
Twitter timeline his he has said this
recently
they have determined that the parces of
India they are genetically closer to the
ancient portions than today's Persian
population what does this mean
it means Persian purchased today's
population is
not the same is not completely descended
from the old persons a lot of foreign
genetics especially Arabic genetic
Arabian genetics uh
introgressed into Persia in roughly the
past 1000 years so the Indian parses are
much closer to the ancient Persians than
today's versions which tells you which I
think we all understand the mechanism
the mechanics and dynamics of how the
genetics of Persia must have been
changed in the past thousand years yeah
we all know that it did not happen to
persons in India they were not temp you
know the they were not forced to
intermarry with Indians there was no
forcible anything done to them they were
able to live any way they wanted and
they were allowed the freedom to do that
in India and we know what happened to
them in Persia right
that's first thing but when did the
policies first come to India about 1200
or so years ago right the problem with
this statement that this lady havovi
Gandhi is doing is making is that the
the chavra surname is older than that
have
are known to have lived in in Western
India much before the Parsi uh Escape
into India so that itself demonstrates
that this this claim is false and this
lady hawawi Gandhi has a
surname Gandhi it's not a particular
name
the what the process did is that after
they escaped to India they took up
various Indian surname so all the local
western Indian surnames Mehta and I
don't know I whatever whatever surnames
of people had in Gujarat they acquired
these surnames right Gujarat and Western
India and all that so some of the
surnames don't make much sense like Tata
and Baba and all that
um the parts had many great people no
doubt about that but that happened
because India was magnanimous enough to
give them shelter when nobody else was
willing to give them shelter right
and for the longest time the parses were
just an ordinary community in India but
when the British took over the parts
suddenly shot the party suddenly shot to
prominence and they started suddenly
becoming Superstars why because the
British singled out the parsies for
preferential treatment the British had
this policy of divide and Rule and they
singled out the parsley Community this
tiny parsley Community for preferential
treatment they gave them all the
Privileges that they would not give to
the rest of the the Indian communities
and that's why the person suddenly
became Mega Rich industrialized and what
not right
and we also know the policy rule in in
OPM smuggling and drug smuggling which
was done on the behest of Victoria Queen
Victoria
we know the party participation the the
participation of various Parsi merchants
and Traders in the the Opium oppression
in China we know all that it's all a
matter of record look it up look it up
right and that's why I said that the
policies were given preferential
treatment and that's why they became so
so dominant and all that and all their
wealth is thanks to this British
preferential treatment otherwise they
are no different from any other Indian
Community especially I would say that
the people of uh the the so so-called
baniya people of Rajasthan the marwaris
ETC even of Gujarat these people have
entrepreneurship in the blood if they
had been given the same privileges that
the policies they would have transformed
the whole whole world right but that did
not happen so that is the thing now
obviously some parses have contributed
something good to the country they have
the tatas and the
uh whatever yeah whoever else we we also
have the example of what's his name uh
Sam maneksho who uh was one of the major
uh participants in the Bangladesh
Liberation War well please let's
understand this if some manager wasn't
there if somebody else was in Space the
same result would have been accomplished
it's not like Indians are less capable
than parsies people forget the name of
Lieutenant General Sagat Singh rathore
he is one of the unsung heroes of the
1971 Bangladesh Liberation War nobody
speaks about it much and he's also one
of the unsung heroes of the 1967 victory
of India against China
nobody even knows that India and China
went to War in 1967 because your
journalists in your favorite history
teachers will not tell you this India
and China fought a War in 1967 and the
Chinese were defeated
and one of the heroes of that Indian
victory was Lieutenant General Sagat
Singh rathore who also was instrumental
in ensuring the Indian victory in 1971
but all the credit goes to San manak
show do you know what Lieutenant General
looked like let me see
1971 uh surrender
Pakistan surrender
let's see let's see the picture
let me put that on the screen shall we
and let's let me show you what
Lieutenant General Sagat Singh rathore
looked like
uh where's the image let's put an image
on the screen so if you see uh where's
the image let's take this one for
instance
so
over here you see that Pakistani fellow
nyazi with the pen in his hand
you go right above him you have this
gentleman in this olive green shirt
uh which is second from right that is
Lieutenant General Sagat Singh rathore
one of the great warriors India has
produced so let's not try to attribute
everything to one individual 1971 was a
collective Victory many people
participated in that and it for some
reason we try we over emphasize the role
of one individual I am not saying that
uh that Sam maneksha was not a great son
obviously it was a great Soldier it was
one of India's greatest soldiers one of
India's greatest military leaders but if
some manek show wasn't there many other
leaders many other soldiers generals
could have taken up the role same role
and they would accomplish the same
result if not a better result so let's
not try to
defy a certain Community who have
greatly
benefited from the preferential
treatment given to them through no fault
of their own by India's foreign
occupiers parses are a wonderful people
I like the parsis I don't have anything
against the passage I am just stating
historical facts so let's not get all
riled up and emotional about this I'm
sure Hawaii Gandhi is a very nice lady
with a Gujarati surname you know nothing
against anybody I'm just stating
historical facts we have to understand
how Indian Society ended up the way it
is today
how did some people end up so rich
any person who was who was very rich in
1947 became Rich only through the treat
the preferential treatment given to them
by the British you could not become rich
in British occupied India unless you
served the British please understand
that
in this doesn't apply only to the
parsies this also applies to various
other industrialists
who became monumentally rich
during British rule can you think of any
homework homework go on find it out
okay I have so many questions today that
I was not able to answer let me I
apologize to all I had taken so many
more but I think we have almost reached
the end of today's thing so as is our
traditional custom let me take some
questions from the live chat from the
live chat uh why is this Habibi good
thing going on
Habibi Gandhi ah some interesting names
come up going cars in beerless uh who
else tatas we know we know tatas Cyrus
Cyrus We Know Cyrus uh whoever Cyrus the
tatas we know tatas are there
and so on and so forth yeah yeah so yeah
many of these uh industrialists who
became industrialists or whatever they
did so because the British gave them
special privileges
all right
um
let's take some other questions now from
the um
from the the
live chat Akshay Kumar oh nice to have a
Bollywood influence here uh the late
the late General bipin Singh rawat said
that India has to be prepared for a 2.5
front war is the Nia Crackdown on on PFI
the 0.5 front War so you know the Nia
and whatever it does is is sometimes
visible some mostly it is invisible and
whatever they're doing is obviously to
secure India's national interest
internally is and externally so I cannot
be sure exactly what is happening uh
there are reports in the past few days
of some Crackdown happening on certain
organizations it could be part of that
it could be part of something else we
don't quite know but I think the ni is
doing well and I think we have to be
constantly on our toes and constantly
prepared for the 2.5 front War
especially the 0.5 internal angle that
General bipin Roberts spoke about yes
uh okay
Suarez says As We Know Pakistan is
dealing with massive flooding on the
schedule speak about the Indus River
treaty and how and why these Rivers can
strategically be important for India in
time of war the Indus River treaty was
something that was uh done between India
and Pakistan during the
1960s on 50 somewhere there under the
auspicious leadership of The Magnificent
Monumental and magnanimous Shri
jawaharlal nehruji so in according to
this treaty which was brokered by the
IMF of the World Bank most likely the
World Bank according to this treaty
India gave up 80 of the Waters of the
indusindu region to Pakistan India can
only use 20 the rest is all for Pakistan
I don't know why this is the most
incredibly lopsided treaty in in human
history most likely even when you are
defeated by a foreign power you don't
get such a lopsided treaty so that's
what India
accepted under the auspicious
magnificent Galactic leadership of Sri
naruji so that's the Indus River treaty
now India is under no obligation to uh
keep uh accepting a treaty that is not
in its favor the Americans have
demonstrated numerous times that they
can walk away from a treaty the Iran
nuclear deal they had signed it was all
officially done but they walked away
from it under President Trump the
Chinese had this deal with the UK about
Hong Kong One Nation two systems that
sort of thing they walked away from the
from the treaty they said it's no longer
legitimate or acceptable and we no
longer recognize it so you can always
walk back walk away from a treaty even
though you may have signed it and this
was this was signed such a long time ago
so
if India was to reclaim the waters and
say okay we no longer recognize the
treaty you can go to hell
can India do that India can do that but
is it is India in a position to do that
to be able
to withhold those Waters from Pakistan
you need infrastructure on the rivers in
the Indian regions where the rivers flow
in the Indian Territory you need to
build multiple dams and reservoirs and
canals you need to build this massive
infrastructure to be able to do this at
a moment's notice and then you also need
to have fortifications and air defenses
and other defenses to ward off any
Pakistani military threat to the
infrastructure you've created have we
even started doing this
we have not started doing this which
means that we are not in a position
to strategically use the waters against
Pakistan
if we make any statements it's empty
words what does that mean
we know that the current uh
oh my God sir you don't know to say
sorry I have the utmost and most
magnificent respect for you sir I'm so
blessed that you have made an appearance
here thank you very much anyhow Pakistan
so
the current government has a
significantly harder stance against
Pakistan right we know we have seen
actions the Bala Court thing the
surgical strikes and various other
things
the prime minister of India has shown
conciliatory measures against Pakistan
he has uh he visited Mr Nawaz Sharif for
his granddaughter's wedding he went
there with a gift and blessed the girl
and all that so India tried
to to make friends with Pakistan but the
pakistanis kept on doing terrorism and
then there had to be punished
appropriately
so this government has a hard line
stance against Pakistan if this
government will not compromise with
India's national interest when it comes
to Pakistan or anybody else so why is
this government not building damn
infrastructure another water
infrastructure on the river so that we
can
walk away from the 1971 treaty from the
from the industry most likely it is
because Pakistan is a temporary nation
and when Pakistan is no longer a thing
then we don't need any such
infrastructure
think about that
all right so
so that's that's what I think that's
what I think what's going on
uh right
um
okay any other questions let me see one
or two other questions if we have any
interesting questions
um
uh abhinav says would the Northeast have
been a part of India the British never
colonized us
the north the Far East of India
is not some other part of the world
if the British had not colonized us then
Bangladesh would have been part of India
they partitioned Bengal
Bangladesh would never have been a thing
Bangladesh was independent was a
separate country from 1947 to 1971 it
was part of Pakistan just how many years
is that 24 years
whatever the number is yeah and we could
have reintegrated it but you know so
Bangladesh itself would not have been a
separate country Pakistan would not even
have existed
and when it comes to other parts of
Southeast Asia they may or may not have
been part of India but they would
certainly have been part of Indian
civilization
we would have much closer ties with
Nations like Burma with Thailand with
Laos with Cambodia with the Vietnam with
Indonesia Malaysia and so on so forth if
the British had not colonized us right
in the Northeast would very much have
been part of that it could have been a
part of India I think the Northeast you
know why it looks so different today
it's because of the christianization of
the Northeast which was done actually
after Independence the bulk of it it was
done under the Magnificent and most
gracious auspicious of auspices of his
grace the Holiness
who prohibited the entry of any Hindu uh
religious person into the Northeast but
he facilitated the mass industrial scale
conversion of other people of nagaland
and other other places to Christianity
via American missionaries so that's why
today the culture is so different
otherwise the people of nagaland who had
the traditional animistic and other
beliefs they could have regarded
themselves there are certain Naga people
people
who belong to certain so-called Naga
tribes who practice Hinduism in in the
state of Manipur so you know Northeast
would definitely have been a part of
India the British colonization did a lot
of Destruction when it comes to India
they did not do anything good for India
in any way whatsoever it's not like the
Northeast is a gift of the British to
India what nonsense it's not the same
it's not it's not the case at all
which has historically belonged to
Manipur Mr nehru gave it to up to Burma
it was
it was taken by Burma on lease from the
kingdom of Manipur
it was still Manipur territory it was
still Indian Territory Mr Nero just gave
it up
this is the kind of um the great
missionary so you know British
occupation and its result which was Mr
Nero and various other leaders they did
more harm to India than any good at all
so yeah that is where we are and I think
we will end today's session over here
thank you very much to everybody for
your questions this was a very
interesting episode as always very good
questions so uh we're gonna end it here
thank you very much to everybody and
next weekend I will not be doing live
streams because unfortunately I'm
traveling but I will make sure to put
something up interesting on the channel
around that time so I will see you as
soon as is humanly possible very soon in
the in the meanwhile take care of
yourselves keep moving forward raise
your standards and let's conquer the
world
take care